In this lesson on multivariate visualizations,
在这一章节的课程中
we'll continue to use the two datasets from the previous lessons.
我们将继续使用之前课上用到的两个数据集
One for creature statistics from the Pokemon video game series and one on
一个是精灵宝可梦系列游戏里的角色数据
fuel efficiency for sedans manufactured from 2013 to 2018.
另一个是 2013 年到 2018 年生产的汽车燃油效率
We'll start here with the car dataset.
我们从这个汽车数据集开始
In this video, I'm going to look at how to use
在这个视频中 我们来看一下如何在散点图中
shape or size to encode a third variable in a scatter plot.
使用形状和大小编码第三个变量
In the last lesson,
在上一章节
we created a scatter plot of fuel mileage against engine size.
我们创建了有关燃油里程和发动机排量大小的散点图
I've taken a random subset of 200 cars to reduce
我随机选取了 200 辆车的子数据集
over-plotting and combine that with a small amount of horizontal jitter.
来避免图表的重叠 并且添加了一些水平抖动
Are there differences between cars with automatic transmission and
在燃油效率和发动机大小方面
manual transmission in terms of fuel efficiency and engine size?
自动档和手动档的车辆之间存在差异吗？
Since transmission type is categorical,
因为变速器类型属于分类变量
shape is a good encoding to use.
形状是一个比较好的编码方式
In both the red plot and scatter functions,
不管在 regplot 还是 scatter 函数里
the marker parameter can be used to set the shape of the plotted points.
都可以用 marker 参数来设定数据点的形状
Unfortunately, in both cases,
可惜的是 在两个函数里
the parameter can only take a single string.
该参数都只能是单个字符串
This means that we need to create a loop to plot each subset of the data one by one.
这意味着 我们需要创建一个循环来逐一绘制每个类别的数据
First of all, I set up
首先 我创建了
a list of lists ttype markers with my mapping of levels to symbol types.
一个列表组成的列表 ttype_markers 其中每个列表包含类别及其对应的符号
Cars with automatic transmission will be circles set by
自动档将由 o 代表的圆圈表示
the string O and cars with manual transmission will be triangles set by the string caret.
手动挡将由 ^ 代表的三角型来表示
I've set it up as a list of lists rather than a dictionary
我用了一个列表的列表 而不是字典
so that I can have finer control of the order in which the levels are plotted.
这样我就可以更好地控制绘制的顺序了
Then I'm going to loop over the list elements.
现在我将遍历列表里的每一个元素
I use ttype to select only the plots with matching
我用 ttype 变量来筛选符合该变速器类型的数据
transmission type and set the marker and the regplot function.
然后在 regplot 函数中设置 marker 参数
The result is this plot.
结果是这张图
It's worth noting that with multiple regplot calls,
值得一提的是 重复调用 regplot 函数
all of the data is plotted on the same axis and
每一次都将绘制在同一个坐标系中
different colors have been automatically assigned to each call.
并且每一次调用会自动设置为不同的颜色
This is fortunate since the two transmission types have a lot of overlap.
这样刚好 因为两种变速器类别的数据有很多重叠
The main difference between transmission types that we can see in this plot is that
图中可以看到两种类别车辆最大的不同是
the cars with the highest fuel efficiency are all of automatic type.
燃油效率最高的汽车都是自动档的
We can add a legend to the plot by using Matplotlib's legend function.
我们可以使用 Matplotlib 里的 legend 函数绘制图例
As an argument to the function,
作为函数的参数
we give a list of labels to place on the legend.
我们传入一个包含类别名称的列表
One for each regplot call.
与调用 regplot 函数的顺序一致
Instead of transmission type,
除了变速器类型
what if we wanted to add carbon dioxide emissions as a third variable?
如果我们想要把二氧化碳排放量作为第三个变量呢？
Since CO2 is numeric,
因为该变量是数值类型的
one encoding we could use is marker size.
我们可以使用大小作为编码类型
In Matplotlib scatter function,
在 Matplotlib 的 scatter 函数中
we can set marker size with the S parameter,
我们可以用 s 这个参数来设置大小
setting it to the name of the column we want to map it to, CO2.
把它设为我们想要可视化的列名 co2
However, since I'm using regplot,
但是 因为我用的是 regplot
I need to set the parameter as part of a dictionary on the scatter
我需要将该参数写入 scatter_kws
keywords parameter and explicitly
这个 scatter 的关键字参数字典中
assigned it the full series rather than just the column name.
而且要将其修改为 Series 数据 而不仅仅是列名
The trend seems pretty clear to me here,
这里的趋势似乎很明显了
but let's reduce the marker size somewhat so that we can see more of the points.
但是让我们再缩小下圆圈的大小 这样我们能够看到更多的数据点
It looks like as engine size increases,
从图上似乎能得出这样的结论：随着发动机大小的增大
there is a higher level of CO2 emissions.
二氧化碳的排放量也在增大
It also seems that the less fuel efficient cars also tend to have higher emissions,
而且 即使汽车具有同等大小的发动机 其燃油效率越低
even at similar engine sizes.
其二氧化碳的排放量也越大
Matplotlib will naturally associate the area of the points with input values.
Matplotlib 会自动将变量的数值大小映射到点的面积上
We have a small problem here when it comes to adding a legend.
但说到图例 我们这里遇到一个小的问题
We only have one scatter plot series plotted,
我们这里只画出了一个 Series 数据
so the legend will only give us a single dot.
所以图例只给了我们一个单独的点
As a work around, we can add
要解决这个问题 我们可以添加
dummy scatter plot sequences so that we can construct our legend.
虚拟散点图序列来构建图例
When we use plotting functions in Matplotlib and Seaborn,
当我们调用 Matplotlib 和 Seaborn 里的绘图函数
we actually get plotting objects back.
实际上会返回图表对象
We haven't been storing them so far since we've not needed them,
目前为止 我们并没有存储这些对象 因为并不需要
but this is one case where we want them.
但现在 我们就需要用到它了
Let's set up a loop to go over
让我们创建一个循环
three CO2 values that we want to use for the size legend reference.
遍历三个我们想要用来作为co2 参考图例的值
Inside the loop, use the scatter function to create scatter plot objects,
在循环里面 使用 scatter 函数来创建 scatter 图表对象
setting the necessary point sizes.
并传入想要的大小
The first two arguments for x and y positions are empty lists,
前两个关于 x 和 y 位置的参数是空列表
so no points are actually plotted.
所以它们实际没有绘制任何点
I'm also adding a color argument so that all of our new series share a consistent color.
我还添加了一个颜色参数 使得所有的 Series 数据都使用同一个颜色
Finally, I'm going to set up a list to store all of our dummy scatter plot objects.
最后 我们将设置一个列表来存储所有的虚拟散点图对象
In the legend function,
在 legend 函数中
if there's only one argument,
如果只传入一个参数
then it is assumed to be the labels for the plot objects.
那这个参数代表的就每一类别的标签
With two arguments, the first one is a list of objects to be
如果传入两个参数 第一个参数代表的是图例要代表的对象列表
depicted in the legend and the second one is a list of labels.
第二个则是名称标签的列表
I've also added a title argument to give the units of the legend values.
我还使用了 title 这个参数 給图例的数值标明单位